Guide to the Thomas Parran Papers, 1892-1968 UA.90.F14
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Addresses and Meetings, VI.
  - Commencement address Skidmore Colleges Saratoga Springs, N.Y., June 6, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 491)
  - National Health Conference Washington, D.C., July 18, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 492)
  - Abbott Laboratories North Chicago, October 7, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 493)
  - Association of Military Surgeons, October 14, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 494)
  - Future of Public Health in the United States Association of American Medical Colleges, October 24, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 495)
  - The Health of the Nation American Public Health Association, Kansas City, October 25, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 496)
  - Dedication - U.S. Public Health Service Hospital Forth Worth, Texas, October 28, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 497)
  - The Health Record of the South Cooperative Committee, Washington, D.C., November 7, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 498)
  - The Road Ahead in Public Health Wilmington New Century Club, Wilmington, November 9, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 499)
  - The Road Ahead in Public Health Virginia Peninsula Academy of Medicine, Newport News, Va., November 21, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 500)
  - Looking Forward in Public Health Detroit Town Hall, Detroit, December 7, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 501)
  - Health for Rural America American Farm Bureau Federation, New Orleans, December 13, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 502)
  - Educating the Nation Toward Health School Life, January, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 503)
  - Alpha Omega Fraternity Cleveland, December 27, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 504)
  - Montgomery, Ala., January 10, 1959 (Box 39, Folder 505)
  - Rough notes - speeches not written, 1939 (Box 39, Folder 506)
  - Public Health for the Individual General Federation of Women's Clubs, Washington, D.C., January 20, 1939 (Box 39, Folder 507)
  - Congratulatory Letters on Award of Snow Medal, February 1, 1939 (Box 39, Folder 508)
  - The Integration of Health Principles Catholic University School of Nursing Washington, D.C., January 7, 1939 (Box 39, Folder 509)
  - American Social Hygiene Association Washington, D.C., February 1, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 510)
  - Johns Hopkins University Y.M.C.A. Baltimore, February 7, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 511)
  - Trinity College Washington, D.C., March 7, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 512)
  - Balancing the Health Budget - G.U. broadcast Washington, D.C., March 8 10, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 513)
  - Munitions for National Fitness Drug, Chemical Allied Trades, New York City, March 9, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 514)
  - Maryland Women's Club Chevy Chase, March 15, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 515)
  - Louisiana Association of Public Health Workers New Orleans, March 20-31, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 516)
  - Cancer broadcast Washington, D.C., April 3, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 517)
  - Tuberculosis broadcast Washington, D.C., April 5, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 518)
  - Health Needs of the Nation American Red Cross, Washington D.C., April 25, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 519)
  - League of Nation's Building, New York World's Fair, May 2, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 520)
  - Medicine in a Changing Society Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., June 1, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 521)
  - Centerville, Md., June 2, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 522)
  - The Right to Health and How to Win It. National Conference of Social Work, Buffalo, June 20, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 523)
  - National Cancer Institute Cornerstone laying, (Photographs), June 24, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 524)
  - The Outlook for a National Health Program National Conference of Catholic Charities, Denver, August 7, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 525)
  - Medicine in a Changing World California Academy of Medicine, San Francisco, August 26, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 526)
  - Medicine in a Changing World Linn County Medical Society, Cedar Rapids, Iowa, September 7, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 527)
  - Cancer and the Public Health International Cancer Congress, Atlantic City, September 13, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 528)
  - National Health - Today's Challenge Monmouth County Organization for Social Service, Redbank, N.J., September 21, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 529)
  - Medical Education, Research, and the Public Health University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, October 12, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 530)
  - This folder contains miscellaneous clippings, speeches, surveys, editorials, correspondence of various dates (Box 40, Folder 531)
  - Comments on book Shadow on the Land (1937-38) (There is a small part of the book in this folder - it is a sample of information found in book) (Box 40, Folder 532)
  - Medicine in a Changing World University of Michigan Medical School, Ann Arbor, October 13, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 533)
  - Radio broadcast - WCAE Pittsburgh, October 18, 1939 (Box 41, Folder 534)
  - The Surgeon General speaks re: National Health Program The Modern Hospital, December, 1939 (Box 41, Folder 535)
  - Railway Surgeons and the Public Health New York and New England Association of Railway Surgeons, New York City, November 3, 1939 (Box 41, Folder 536)
  - Shadow on the Land- Book material (Box 41, Folder 537)
  - Shadow on the Land- book reviews (Box 41, Folder 538)
  - Shadow on the Land- correspondence (Box 41, Folder 539)
  - Shadow on the Land- miscellaneous correspondence, clippings (Box 41, Folder 540)
  - National Social Hygiene Day Chicago, February 1, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 541)
  - Dentistry as a Health Service Dental Cetenary Celebration, Baltimore, March 17-19, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 542)
  - Cancer broadcast Washington, D.C., March 29, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 543)
  - Reprint - No Defense for Any of Us New Health Sentinels of the South, April, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 544)
  - Tuberculosis broadcast New York City, April 2, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 545)
  - American Academy of Pediatrics Washington, D.C., Mayflower Hotel, April 4-6, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 546)
  - Nutrition and National Health. Sedgwick Memorial Lecture, Boston, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, April 11, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 547)
  - Radio broadcast, I.V.N.S., April 20, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 548)
  - North Carolina Health Needs. North Carolina Conference for Social Services, Winston Salem, April 21, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 549)
  - "Sifting the Shadow of Syphilis" Reader's Digest, April 27, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 550)
  - Pan American Directors of Health Washington, D.C., May 1-8, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 551)
  - Public Health Aspects of Syphilis. Massachusetts Medical Society, Boston, May 22, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 552)
  - Parallel Lines of Defense University of Maryland, June 1, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 553)
  - St. John's College, June 11, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 554)
  - Health and Medical Preparedness Conference of Health Officers and Public Health Nurses, Saratoga Springs, N.Y., June 25, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 555)
  - "Cancer and Old Age" Scientific Monthly, October, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 556)
  - Building Health Defenses Southern Medical Association, Louisville, Ky., November 14, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 557)
  - Symposium on Alcoholism Philadelphia, December 29, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 558)
  - Syphilis Prevalence in State of New York, (1956-1940) (Box 42, Folder 559)
  - Our Longer Life Metropolitan Opera Co. broadcast, January 18, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 560)
  - Cancer broadcast WJSV, April 1, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 561)
  - Public Health and the National Defense New England Health Institute, Boston, April 2, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 562)
  - Medicine in England Now. American College of Physicians, Boston, April 26, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 563)
  - Mother's Day broadcast Washington, D.C., May 11, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 564)
  - The Thrust Ahead in Public Health. State Charities Aid Association, New York, May 20, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 565)
  - Volunteers in Health Defense. General Federation of Women's Clubs, Atlantic City, May 21, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 566)
  - Country Journal Program - broadcast Washington, D.C., May 24, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 567)
  - Food and Defense. American Forum of the Air Washington, D.C., May 25, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 568)
  - The Job Ahead. National Nutrition Conference, Washington, D.C., May 28, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 569)
  - The Function of Public Health in Defense. American Medical Association, Cleveland, June 3, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 570)
  - Defense Health Activities New York Conference of Mayors and Other Municipal Officials, Albany, June 11, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 571)
  - Listen America NBC, June 13, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 572)
  - Red Cross Nurses' Training Camp, June 26, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 573)
  - Statement by Surgeon General to House Committee investigating National Defense Migration, July 18, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 574)
  - Gibson Island Vitamin Conference, July 23, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 575)
  - Nurses for Defense NBC broadcast, September 22, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 576)
  - Walker-Gordon Laboratories Plainsboro, N.J. Radio talk by Dr. Parran on National Farm and Home hour, October 7, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 577)
  - Nutrition and War American Academy of Pediatrics Boston, October 9, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 578)
  - Ehrlich celebration, Jade Room, Waldorf Astoria, October 11, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 579)
  - Message to American Bakers Association Statler Hotel, Boston, October 13, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 580)
  - Better Parenthood Week luncheon and radio broadcast WJSV-CBS, Mayflower Hotel, Washington, D.C., October 20, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 581)
  - Health Nutrition and National Defense (Read at Special Convocation, University of Toronto), October 24, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 582)
  - Public Health and Pan American Defense. American Public Health Association, Atlantic City, October, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 583)
  - Hospital administrators Washington, D.C., October 30, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 584)
  - Association of Grocery Manufacturers of America, Inc. Waldorf Hotel, New York, November 6, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 585)
  - Women's activities in Civilian Defense Government auditorium, Washington, D.C., November 8, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 586)
  - Toward a Stronger America. Annual convention of American Bottlers of Carbonated Beverages, Municipal auditorium, Philadelphia, November 12, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 587)
  - American Pharmaceutical Manufactures Association Mayflower Hotel, Washington, D.C., December 8, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 588)
  - The U.S. Conference of Mayors Mayflower Hotel, Washington, D.C., January 12, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 589)
  - The Ramparts of Health State-Wide Public Health Committee, Orlando, Fla., January 16, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 590)
  - Transcript for a nursing organization. NBC Studios, Translux Building, January, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 591)
  - The National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis. Broadcast over NBC from the White House, January 19, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 592)
  - National Farm and Home Hour, NBC (WOL) Farm Security Medical Program for Low Income Farm Families, January 26, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 593)
  - Defense of Our Health General Federation of Women's Clubs, Mayflower Hotel, January 26, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 594)
  - Birthday Ball broadcast (WOL), January 28, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 595)
  - "Health Solidarity in the Americase" Published in America Clinica, February, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 596)
  - Wartime Problems of the Public Health Service. Annual congress on Medical Education and Licensure, American Medical Association, Chicago, February 16, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 597)
  - "Saving Health Among All Nations" Survey Graphic, March 1942 (Box 43, Folder 598)
  - Nutrition and Public Health Dept. of Agriculture, March 18, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 599)
  - Opening remarks at Joint Meeting of National Conference of Governmental Industrial Hygienists and Subcommittee of Industrial Health and Medicine, Social Security Building Auditorium, April 9, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 600)
  - WPA radio transcription New Interior Building, April 28, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 601)
  - National Hospital Association of the Suburban Hospital Association, Leland Junior High School, Chevy Chase, MD., May 12, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 602)
  - The Health Needs of the Nation Address before 1942 Biennial Nurses' Convention Chicago, May 18, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 603)
  - Food Is Building A New America. Star Forum - Blue Network Washingtons D.C., May 25, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 604)
  - Rural Health Conservation, Address given at second Inter American Conference of Agriculture Mexico City, July 6-16, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 605)
  - Connecticut Judicial Department New London, October 15, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 606)
  - Civilian Health in Wartime Inter-State Postgraduate Medical Association Chicago, October 26, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 607)
  - Civilian Medical Care in Total War Presented at Southern Medical Association Richmond, VA., November 11, 1942 (Box 44, Folder 608)
  - The Health of Our Nation in Wartime Annual conference of Secretaries and Editors, American Medical Association, Chicago, November 20, 1942 (Box 44, Folder 609)
  - Chicago Rapid Treatment Center, November 29, 1942 (Box 44, Folder 610)
  - The Hospital's Stake in the U.S. Cadet Nurse Corps. Pub. in The Modern Hospital, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 611)
  - Problems in Wartime Civilian Medical Practice Bulletin of the American College of Surgeons, War Issue, No. II. (Box 44, Folder 612)
  - National Radio Forum Washington, D.C., January 6, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 613)
  - Signal Corps, War Department, January 20, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 614)
  - Nutrition and Health Luncheon meeting at Mayflower Hotel, (Sponsored by Nutrition Div., Office of Defense, Health and Welfare Services and D.C. Nutrition Committee, January 21, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 615)
  - Conference on Traumatic War Neuroses Among Merchant Seamen. Academy of Medicine, New York City, January 28, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 616)
  - Doctors At War No. 6 American Medical Association. Broadcast, January 30, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 617)
  - Southeastern Regional Conference on Social Hygiene Atlanta, February 3, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 618)
  - State of the Nation's Health National Chamber of Commerce Health Advisory Council Friday, February 5, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 619)
  - Pittsburgh Personnel Association, February 11, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 620)
  - Annual Congress on Medical Education and Licensure American Medical Association, Chicago, February 15, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 621)
  - Science and the Future. Address before awards dinner of second annual Science Talent Search, March 2, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 622)
  - Opening remarks at 41st annual Conference of State and Territorial Health Officers. Washington, D.C., March 24, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 623)
  - Food for the Working Adolescent. Radio dialogue for New York Academy of Medicine. CBS - WTOP, May 1, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 624)
  - National Health in the First Year of War by Surgeon General Parran before Appropriations Committee, May 6, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 625)
  - Washington Reports on Rationing, June 6, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 626)
  - Venereal Disease, The Great Ally of the Axis. Federal-State War Conference on Social Protection. Trenton, N.J., June 18, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 627)
  - Statement by Surgeon General on 25th Anniversary of Soviet Commissariat of Health of U.S.S.R., July 10, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 628)
  - Functions of Command. Given at graduation exercises of Officers' Candidate School. Quantico, VA., July 14, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 629)
  - "Here's To a Healthier World" Radio broadcast on Farm and Home Hour, July 16, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 630)
  - Broadcast to New Zealand, Office of War Information, July 19, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 631)
  - Statement by Dr. Parran at luncheon meeting of U.S. Cadet Nurse Corps. New York City, August 16, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 632)
  - Public Health Tomorrow American Hospital Association, Buffalo, September 16, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 634)
  - Transcription for Red Cross Nutrition Radio Show, September 22, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 635)
  - Pandemic Influenza 15th annual meeting Scientific Assembly of the D.C. Medical Society, October 1, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 636)
  - Strategy Against the Global Spread of Disease Given by Surgeon General at 72nd annual meeting of American Public Health Association, October 13, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 637)
  - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis Radio broadcast, CBS, New York City, October 13, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 638)
  - Teamwork on the Health Front. Given at Symposium of War Medicine, 51st annual meeting of Association of Military Surgeons of the U.S. Philadelphia, October 21, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 639)
  - Public Health Schools and the Nation's Health. Dedication exercises of new School of Public Health, University of Michigan, November 8, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 640)
  - "Justice Guilding and Charity Helping" National Conference of Catholic Charities, Buffalo, November 14, 1943 (Box 45, Folder 641)
  - Health Problems Ahead Southern Medical Association, Cincinnati, November 18, 1943 (Box 45, Folder 642)
  - Commencement Day Exercises St. Louis University School of Medicine, November 19, 1943 (Box 45, Folder 643)
  - Health Manpower U.S. Conference of Mayors, Chicago, (Read by Dr. Meriwether), January 20, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 644)
  - "Health is on the March" Office of War Information Radio Transcription, January 28, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 645)
  - Time on Their Hands Concluding talk for "Doctors at War" - American Medical Association radio series. NBC, January 29, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 646)
  - A Health Task for Today and Tomorrow Dr. Parran's trip to Puerto Rico, February 1-12, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 647)
  - The Expanding Field of Public Health and Preventive Medicine Annual Congress on Medical Education and Licensure, A.M.A. Chicago, February 14, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 648)
  - Wanted Health Supplies in War and Peace Presented before Drug, Chemical and Allied Trades Section, New York Board of Trade, March 9, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 649)
  - Nursing in War and Peace Dedication of Nurses Dormitories, Adelphi College, Garden City, L.I., May 6, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 650)
  - Office of War Information Broadcast "Broadway Matinee" WTOP, Washington, D.C., March 13, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 651)
  - State of the Nation's Health Presented at State and Territorial Health Officers Conference, March 21, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 652)
  - The Health of the Nation at hearings before Subcommittee on Appropriation, March 28, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 653)
  - "The Role of the Specialist in Public Health" "Advances in Public Health" Gill Memorial Hospital, Roanoke, VA, Roanoke Academy of Medicine, April 3, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 654)
  - Radio interview with Richard Saton WWDC, April 18, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 655)
  - United Health Action Presented at 5th Pan American Conference of National Directors of Health, April 4, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 656)
  - Return to Life American Design Awards Luncheon, Lord Taylor, New York City, April 20, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 657)
  - World Health - First Milestone on the Road to Lasting Peace Metropolitan Opera Victory Rally Broadcast WMAL, April 29, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 658)
  - Testimony by Dr. Parran on S.1820 and S.1824: School Lunch Programs, May 3, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 659)
  - Problems and Prospects in Public Health, New York Academy of Medicine, New York, May 5, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 660)
  - Planning for National Health. Association of American Physicians, Atlantic City, May 9, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 661)
  - Outlook for Tuberculosis Control in the Civilian Population National Tuberculosis Association, Chicago, May 12, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 662)
  - U. S. Cadet Nurse Corps Induction. Constitution, May 13, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 663)
  - World Affairs Program, May 14, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 664)
  - Trends in Public Health Planning. Annual meeting of American Medical Association, Chicago, June 14, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 665)
  - The Doctor Fights. Radio broadcast CBS - Washingtons D.C., June 13, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 666)
  - Tuberculosis Control Statement by Surgeon General Parran before Subcommittee on Education and Labor on S.l85l, June 13-14, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 667)
  - Maine Medical Association. Rocklands Maine, June 27, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 668)
  - "News for Women" WTOP three-say interview, Washington, D.C., June 30, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 669)
  - Inspection trip to Charleston, Columbia, Savannah, and Atlanta, August 16-19, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 670)
  - Testimony by Surgeon General Parran before Senate Committee on Education and Labor on H.R. 4909, Health Program for Government Employees, August 21, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 671)
  - Statement by Dr. Parran before Pepper Sub-Committee on Wartime Health and Education, July 12, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 672)
  - Hospitals and the Nation's Health Address at dedication of student nurse dormitory, University of California, San Francisco, September 4, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 673)
  - The Doctors Talk It Over. Broadcast for Lederle Laboratories, November 10, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 674)
  - 1944 Christmas Seal Sale two-way radio discussion, Washington, D.C. and Chicago, November 26, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 675)
  - Statement submitted by Dr. Parran (presented by Dr. R.C. Williams) to Subcommittee to Investigate Aid to Physically Handicapped, November 29, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 676)
  - International Health. Pan American Health Day, Pan American Union, December 2, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 677)
  - Testimony before Senate Appropriations Committee by Surgeon General Parrans re: Commissions for Nurses, December 9, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 678)
  - Dentistry in a National Health Program. Horace Wells Dental Centenary, Hartford, Conn., December 11, 1944. (Box 46, Folder 679)
  - Three minute talk on work of the Public Health Service to follow Cavalcade of America Broadcast, December 16, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 680)
  - New Frontiers in Medicine Address given at commencement exercises, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, September 10, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 681)
  - A Clean Bill of Health Reprinted from The Modern Hospital, September, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 682)
  - Radio broadcast with Richard Harkness, NBC, Montreal, September 19, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 683)
  - Today's Global Frontiers in Public Health. Wartime Conferences American Public Health Association. New York City, October 4, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 684)
  - North Carolina Health Education Conference Greensboro, N.C., October 24, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 685)
  - 16th Scientific Assembly of the Medical Society of D.C. Mayflower Hotel, October 7, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 686)
  - Global Frontiers of Public Health Association of Military Surgeons, Hotel Pennsylvania, New York City, November 2, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 687)
  - Radio broadcast WMAL, November 11, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 688)
  - 3rd National Venereal Disease Control Conference St. Louis, November 8-11, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 689)
  - A Message to the Canadian People Transcription by Dr. Parran to be used, November 10, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 690)
  - Over the Horizon in Public Health. Given at dedication of Health Institute AUW-CIO, Detroit. Broadcast over WKAR, January 19, 1945 (Box 46, Folder 691)
  - Testimony of Dr. Parran before House Committee on Military Affairs in support of H.Ro 1284 and H.R. 1666 re: draft of nurses, February 6, 1945 (Box 46, Folder 692)
  - Voluntary Hospital Must Expand Activity to Meet Changing Conditions. Paper by Dr. Parran for delivery at mid-year-conference, American Medical Association, February, 1945 (Box 46, Folder 693)
  - Promised Victory Broadcast in Chicago, National Social Hygiene Day, February 7, 1945 (Box 46, Folder 694)
  - Testimony by Surgeon General Parran at Senate Committee on Education and Labor on S.191, Hospital Construction Facilities, February 27, 1945 (Box 46, Folder 695)
  - Next Steps in Public Health. Given at Institute of Arts and Sciences, Columbia University, March 13, 1945 (Box 46, Folder 696)
  - Testimony by Dr. Parran on H.R. 2277, Nurse Draft Bill before Senate Committee on Military Affairs, March 21, 1945 (Box 46, Folder 697)
  - Today and Tomorrow in Public Health. Public Health Course for General Federation of Women's Clubs, March 29, 1945 (Box 46, Folder 698)